G. D. Hsiung papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Virology Reference Laboratory, 1977-1993; Series V
  - Proposal and operation of the VRL, 1979-1993; Subseries 1
    - Clinical Virology Diagnostic Laboratory, 1983 October (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Letters in Support of a Clinical Virology Diagnostic Laboratory, 1983 October (Box 17, Folder 6)
      Contains letters of support to Paul LeGolvan, Director, Pathology Service, VA Central Office, Washington. D.C., and letters of support, mostly from other VA hospitals to G. D. Hsiung or Leonard Kaplow, Chief, Laoratory Service, VA Medical Center, West Haven.
    - Correspondence and notes, 1983-1984 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Organization and funding, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - VRL opening event, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      The opening event took place on February 22, 1985. The folder contains posters and photographs.
    - Clinical Virology Newsletter, 1984-1987 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Statistics, 1984-1985 and earlier (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Contains some data going back to 1967.
    - Monthly statistics, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Monthly statistics, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Request for Supplemental Funding, 1987 March (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Monthly Statistics, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Monthly Statistics, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Monthly Statistics, 1990-1991 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Paper: "Research and the Establishment of a Virology Reference Laboratory: From Bench Top to Patient Care", 1993 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      Contains G. D. Hsiung's typed draft presented at the First Annual Chautauqua held at the VA Medical Center, White River Junction, Vermont, June 3, 1993, and submitted to VA Research News, July 1, 1993.
    - Photographs and miscellanea (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Survey of VA Medical Centers, 1982; Subseries 2
    G.D. Hsiung sent out survey forms with a cover letter dated February 5, 1982, to all VA Medical Centers across the continental United States. The forms requested information on the hospital's current virology testing procedures, whether they had their own facilities, and if not, where diagnostic tests were done, and whether they were interested in a central VA testing facility. The folders contain the forms returned to Hsiung. Examples of the cover letter can be found in folders 18 and 19.
    - Survey responses: Alabama-Arizona (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Survey responses: California-Colorado (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Survey responses: Florida-Georgia (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Survey responses: Idaho-Iowa (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Survey responses: Kansas-Louisiana (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Survey responses: Maine-Maryland (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Survey responses: Michigan-Minnesota (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Survey responses: Mississippi-Missouri (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Survey responses: Nebraska-North Dakota (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Survey responses: Ohio-Oregon (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Survey responses: Pennsylvania (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Survey responses: South Carolina-South Dakota (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Survey responses: Tennessee (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Survey responses: Texas (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Survey responses: Virginia Washington, D.C. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Survey responses: Washington-West Virginia (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Survey responses: Wisconsin-Wyoming (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Survey Responses, Districts 1-3 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      Includes Massachusetts and New York.
    - Positive Responses from VA Medical Centers,1982 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      These responses contained a letter or commentary in addition to the filled-out survey. Some of these responses also included G. D. Hsiung's cover letter for the survey, dated February 5, 1982.
    - Additional responses, some negative (Box 18, Folder 20)
      The folder contains negative responses to the survey or conflicting responses.
    - Summaries of responses (Box 18, Folder 21)
      This folder contains lists of positive quotes from various VA Medical Centers; "No responses and comments" from VA Medical Centers; "Hospitals with two responses" and whether they agreed; and additional statistics.
- Abstracts, Presentations, and Workshops, Series VI
  - Abstracts, 1955-1990; Subseries 1
    These are summaries submitted ahead of time for papers that the researcher would like to present at a scientific meeting. Usually, accepted abstracts of particular meetings were printed in an issue of a scientific journal (possibly in a Supplement) or in a more ephemeral publication by the meeting organizers. Dr. Hsiung kept her own abstracts, as well as abstracts by researchers in her laboratory, in a three ringed binder.
    - Abstract List,1967-1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      This list includes where the abstracts were published.
    - Abstracts, 1955-1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      This and the following folders contain the texts of abstracts.
    - Abstracts, 1960-1964 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Abstracts, 1965-1969 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Abstracts, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Abstracts, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Abstracts, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Abstracts, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      With lists of published abstracts for 1976 and 1977.
    - Abstracts, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Abstracts, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Abstracts, 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Abstracts, 1985-1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Presentations/Lectures, 1956-1997; Subseries 2
    Most of the folders contain notes and outlines of presentations, rather than the full text of the presentations. The summary lists in folders 1-3 include mostly the more formal presentations at conferences and workshops, while later folders also include some local presentations such as at at Yale or the VA. This subseries overlaps with the material in the series Conferences/Meetings.
    - List of Lectures and Presentations, 1956-1980 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - List of Lectures and Presentations, 1981-1995 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - List of "Invited Lectureship and/or Invited Participant for Special Study-Groups and Workshops," 1969-1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Cytomegalovirus Infections After Renal Transplant", 1974 June (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Presented at the NIH Workshop on Cytomegaloviruses, 1974 June 20.
    - "Cytomegalovirus Infection: An Animal Model", 1976 March 11 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      The folder contains another outline dated January 7, 1976 for a talk on "Cytomegalovirus Infection in Man and Animals." The later presentation, dated March 11, 1976 was labelled "LABMED" and may have been a presentation for the Yale department.
    - "Viral Diagnosis", 1976 September (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Presentation for the Infectious Diseases Group, 1976 September 29
    - "Viral Etiology of Cancer: Herpesvirus or Oncornarivus?", 1976 November (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Expression of Herpesvirus Genome in Cells Derived from Bone Marrow of Latently Infected Guinea Pigs", 1977 April (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Poster presentation done in collaboration with Aldo Gonzalez-Serva for FASEB meeting, Chicago. Includes photographs.
    - 1978 March: "An Animal Model for Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia: L2C Guinea Pig Leukemia" (Box 20, Folder 9)
      By a large group of collaborators.
    - [Viral Diseases], 1978 June 7 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Presented at the University of Colorado, Infectious Diseases.
    - "Oncogenic Viruses", 1978 June 14 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Presented at Montefiore Hospital.
    - "Interaction Between Herpesvirus and Oncornavirus", 1978 November 21 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      Presented to the Department of Pathology, New York University.
    - "Interaction of Herpesvirus and Onconavirus", 1979 January 5 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Presented at the VA Medical Center.
    - "New Aspects of Clinical Virology", 1979 April 12 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Presented at Mount Sinai Medical Center, New York.
    - "Viruses of Guinea Pigs", 1979 October 26 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      Presented at the Medical Virology Seminar.
    - "Genital Herpes: Pathogenesis and Chemotherapy in an Animal Model", 1982 May 21 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      Presented at the Institute of Medical Research of Bennington, Bennington, Vermont. In addition to an outline of the talk, the folder includes correspondence relating to the invitation to give the presentation.
    - "Rapid Detection and Identification of Viral Infections", 1982 May 22 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      Presentation at the Annual Meeting of the New York State Association of Public Health Laboratories in Albany, New York. Folder includes correspondence and a draft of the talk.
    - "Effect of Cyclophosphamide on Acute and Latent Infection of Guinea Pigs with a Lymphotropic Herpesvirus", 1984 March (Box 20, Folder 18)
      Poster presentation for the American Society for Microbiology. Study done by Kenneth Dowler, Stanley McCormick, J. Armstrong, and G. D. Hsiung. Folder contains poster materials, drafts of the article for publication, and photographs.
    - [Herpesvirus Infections], 1984 April (Box 20, Folder 19)
      Presented at the UCLA Herpesvirus Symposium, Keystone, Colorado, April 9-13, 1984
    - "Rapid Viral Diagnosis: Its Role in Patient Care", 1985 April 22 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      Presentation with Marie Landry given at International Symposium in the Biomedical Sciences: Clinical Virology Symposium, Tampa, Florida on April 22, 1985.
    - "Clinical Virology: Its Role in Patient Care", 1985 July (Box 20, Folder 21)
      Presentation to the University of Arkansas Department of Microbiology and Immunology. Includes itinerary for G.D. Hsiung and Dr. B. P. Griffith.
      Conditions Governing Access
      This file is restricted as it contains patient information.
    - "Effect of Cyclosporine A on Guinea Pigs Infected Intranasally with a Lymphotropic Herpesvirus", 1986 March (Box 20, Folder 22)
      Presented by Z. Nagy, T. Jennings, J. A. Armstrong, H. Lucia, and G. D. Hsiung at the American Society for Microbiology Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., March 23-28, 1986. Folder contains an abstract and a copy of the paper.
    - "Introduction to Diagnosis of Viral Infection", 1986 April 21 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      Presentation given at the Second Clinical Virology Symposium in Tampa, Florida. Folder also includes a paper by Marie L. Landry, "Clinical Virology: How to Bridge Laboratory and Physician."
    - "Change Viewpoints in Diagnosis: When the Diagnosis is AIDS", 1987 January 9 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "Effect of Cyclosporine-A Immunosuppression on Guinea Pigs Infected with a Lymphotropic Herpesvirus", 1987 April 3 (Box 20, Folder 25)
      Presented at the American Society for Microbiology regional meeting.
    - "Introductory Remarks", 1987 April 27 (Box 20, Folder 26)
      Presentation for Third Clinical Virology Symposium in Clearwater, Florida.
    - "The Use of Biotinylated DNA In Situ Hybridization and an Avidin-Biotin Immunoperoxidase Technique for Detection of Lymphotropic Herpesvirus Infection", 1987 August 12 (Box 20, Folder 27)
      Poster presentation for the VIIth International Congress of Virology in Alberta, Canada. File contains correspondence, abstract, text, and photographs.
    - "Introduction to Clinical Aspects of Viral Diseases", 1988 May 23 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Introductory remarks for the symposium, "Clinical Aspects of Viral Diseases," at the Clinical Virology Symposium in Clearwater, Florida. The symposium was held in conjunction with the annual meeting of the Pan American Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis.
    - "An Historic Perspective on Clinical Virology and Future Prospects for Rapid Viral Diagnosis" (Wellcome Diagnostic Award Address), 1988 May 23 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      G. D. Gsiung was the recipient of the Wellcome Diagnostics Award for Achievement in Viral Diagnostics. Her address was given in conjunction with the Clinical Virology Symposium and the PAGRVD annual meeting. The folder contains the speech, a draft of the speech, and a news release
    - "In Vitro Antiviral Activity of Newly Synthesized Pyramidine Nucleoside Analogs Against Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) Infection: An Ultrastructural Study", 1988 June 12 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Poster presentation by S. Angerer-Klein, D. Herring, Z. H. Zang, S. H. Chu, Z. H. Chen, B. P. Griffith, and G. D. Hsiung Poster at the IV International Conference on AIDS, Stockholm, Sweden. Folder contains poster materials, conference information, and a draft of a later paper dated September 1988.
    - "The Impact of Antiviral Therapy on Rapid Viral Diagnosis", 1989 September 21 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Invited lecture given as the first speaker in the re-established Bodansky Lectureship series, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas. Folder includes correspondence, an abstract, and an outline of the lecture.
    - "Host-Controlled Variations in the Evaluation of Antiviral Agents", 1990 June 18 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Presentation by G. D. Hsiung at the Fourth International Antiviral Symposium in Taipei, Taiwan.
    - "The Use of Dose-Effect Analysis for Combined Antiviral Effects of Paired Nucleosides Against Cytomegalovirus Replication in the Guinea Pig Model", 1990 June 18 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      Presentation by J. Y. Crouch at the Fourth International Antiviral Symposium in Taipei, Taiwan. The authors were Z. H. Yang, J. Y. Crouch, T. C. Chou, and G. D. Hsiung, all from the Virology Laboratory, VA Medical Center, West Haven.
    - American Type Culture Collection (ATCC) video interview, 1990 August 21 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      The interview took place at the VA in West Haven. Folder contains correspondence, Hsiung's notes, and materials sent by ATCC. Folder does not contain a copy of the interview.
    - "Combined Antiviral Effect and Cytotoxicity of Ganciclovir and Azidothymidine against CMV Infection in Cultured Cells", 1991 April (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Poster presented at International Society for Antiviral Research in New Orleans, Louisiana, April 21-26, 1991. Authors were P. Y. Tian, J. Y. Crouch, and G. D. Hsiung.
    - "Antiviral Antagonism between Zidovudine and Ganciclovir Against HIV and HCMV Replication in Cultured Cells", 1992 April 24 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      Presentation for the Leo Rettger Society, Connecticut Valley Branch of the American Society for Microbiology, University of Hartford, West Hartford. Authors were G. D. Hsiung, D. J. Medina, J. S. Feng, J. S. Crouch, P. Y. Tian, and J. D. Mellors, all from the VA Medical Center, West Haven.
    - "In Vitro and In Vivo Evaluating of Combined Antiviral Effects Against Cytomegalovirus Infection", 1992 November (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Presented at the International Symposium on Research of Antiviral Drugs, Beijing, China, November 5-7, 1992.
    - "Mysteries and Miracles in Diagnostic Virology", 1993 September 23 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Invited seminar given at the Department of Pathobiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs.
    - "Identification of Foamy Virus Type 1 by Electron Microscopy and Indirect Immunofluorescent Staining", 1994 April (Box 21, Folder 12)
      Poster session at the Annual Clinical Virology Symposium and annual meeting of Pan American Group for Rapid Viral Diagnosis, in Clearwater, Florida. The authors of the presentation were D. Medina, G. Paulino, C. Buck, C. K. Y. Fong, and G. D. Hsiung. Folder contains correspondence with Charles Buck and photographs in addition to materials about the poster.
    - "Mysteries and Miracles in Diagnostic Virology", 1995 May 23 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Lecture given at National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland,
    - "The Continued Importance of Virus Isolation", 1995 October 12 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      American Type Culture Collection Lecture.
    - "The Past, Present, and Future of Clinical Virology", 1996 March 30 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      Presentation given in Tainan, Taiwan.
    - "The Role of Cell Culture and Electron Microscopy for the Diagnosis of Viral Infections", 1996 March 31 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      Presented at the Virology Symposium, Tainan, Taiwan.
    - Virology Reference Laboratory, 1997 March (Box 21, Folder 17)
      From a folder labeled "Virology Reference Laboratory, Symposium March 15-16, 1997." It contains information on the VRL that Hsiung founded in the United States and similar laboratories she helped to found in Taiwan and elsewhere. Much of the information is in Chinese. This folder is related to the presentation in the previous folder.
  - Workshops, 1975-1997; Subseries 3
    This subseries may overlap the previous subseries, Presentations/Lectures. The folders are primarily concerned with workshops that G. D. Hsiung organized other than those given through the VA and Yale. It includes workshops G. D. Hsiung organized in Taiwan and China and material on her lengthy travels in these countries where she met with phsycians and scientists, lectured, and consulted. For workshops associated with the VA, see Boxes 15 and 16.
    - List of Diagnostic Virology Workshops, 1962-1996 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Diagnostic Virology Round Table, 1975 August 28 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Contains the participant list for the Diagnostic Virology Round Table held in New York City.
    - Diagnostic Virology (American Society of Virology), 1982 May (Box 22, Folder 3)
      G. D. Hsiung served as convener of the first Diagnostic Virology Workshop at the American Society for Virology annual meeting. The folder contains G. D. Hsiung's introduction on August 2, 1982, the program of the workshop, as well as other papers.
    - Medical and Experimental Virology (Hubei Medical College, China)--Curriculum/Lectures, 1982 October (Box 22, Folder 4)
      G. D. Hsiung was invited by the Chinese Ministry of Health to organize a two-week advanced course in virology for Chinese scientists, held at Hubei Medical College, China. The course was co-sponsored by Hubei Medical College, Hunan Medical College, the Yale-in-China Association, and the Yale University School of Medicine. The folder contains a list of faculty, an outline of the first three lectures by Hsiung, and a list of laboratory procedures. William C. Summers, Frank J. Bia, and Wilma D. Summers were among the Yale faculty participating.
    - Medical and Experimental Virology (Hubei Medical College, China)--Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      This folder contains correspondence, 1982-1984; Frank J. Bia, "Teaching Medical and Experimental Virology in China: Lessons Learned; G. D. Hsiung, "Experience in Teaching Medical and Experimental Virology in the People's Republic of China"; a reprint of G. D. Hsiung, et al, "Yale-China Association Exchange Programs in Medical Sciences: Past, Present, and Future, Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 54 (1981): 1-9; an issue of "China Update," March 1981; maps; and news clippings.
    - Clinical Virology Mini Residency (VA), 1983 September (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Participants at the "Mini-Residency," September 12-16, were from various VA Medical Centers. Folder contains a list of participants, the program, and photographs. The dinner program on September 15 was a tribute to Wallace P. Rowe. See Box 10, folders 21-24.
    - Clinical Virology Workshop II (Hubei, China), 1984 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Folder contains only a list of slides and an outline from a previous lecture, "Laboratory Diagnosis of Virus Infection," with C. K. J. Wong.
    - Diagnostic Virology Wet Workshop (ATCC), 1985 November 18-22 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      G. D. Hsiung was workshop director for the Diagnostic Virology Wet Workshop held by the American Type Culture Collection in Rockville, Maryland, November 18-22, 1985.
    - Third Workshop: Medical and Molecular Virology (Hubei Medical College)--Correspondence, 1986 October 6-17 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Directed by G. D. Hsiung and held at Hubei Medical College, Wuhan, Hubei, China.
    - Third Workshop: Medical and Molecular Virology (Hubei Medical College)--Curriculum/Lectures, 1986 October (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - International Workshop on Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan), April 1994 -- Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      G. D. Hsiung was invited to organize a workshop in Tainan, Taiwan in conjunction with the International Symposium on Viral and Chlamydial Infections. The workshop, "Advanced Virology," was held April 6-10 at the National Cheng Kung University Medical College. Hsiung arrived in February, visited a number of institutions, met with various researchers, and consulted on organizing a diagnostic virology laboratory.
    - International Workshop on Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan), April 1994-- Dr. Hsiung's schedule in Taiwan and miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - International Workshop for Diagnosis of Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Taiwan) - Curriculum/Participants, 1994 April 6-10 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Directed by G. D. Hsiung and held in Tainan, Taiwan, April 6-10, 1994. Folder includes a photograph of the participants.
    - International Workshop on Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) - Lectures, 1994 April 6-10 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - International Workshop on Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) - Laboratory Exercises, 1994 April 6-10 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Suggestions for equipping a virology laboratory and encouraging research in Taiwan, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Professor and Expert Advisor at Cheng Kung University Medical College, Taiwan -- Correspondence, 1995 February-May (Box 22, Folder 17)
      In February 1995, G. D. Hsiung received an invitation to come to the National Cheng Kung University Medical College, Tainan, Taiwan as a "Professor and Expert Advisor to assist us to establish a diagnostic laboratory in our Department of Pathology." File also contains photographs of boxes of journals shipped to Taiwan.
    - G. D.'s Hsiung's schedule and notes on activities in Taiwan, 1995 March-April (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Clinical Conference with Case Presentations, Taiwan -- Lectures, 1995 March-April (Box 22, Folder 19)
      This series of weekly lectures was set up by G. D. Hsiung. Much of the material is in Chinese.
    - Additional notes, Taiwan, 1995 March-April (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - ATCC Diagnostic Virology Workshop, Rockville, Maryland, 1995 October (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - 1996 March-April: International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) -- correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      The workshop was held at the National Cheng Kung University Medical College, Tainan, Taiwan. G. D. Hsiung arrived several weeks earlier to visit colleagues and consult.
    - 1996 March-April: International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) -- itinerary (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Folder contains G. D. Hsiung's calendar and notes on each day during travel from March 5 to April 3, 1996.
    - International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) -- Participants/schedule, 1996 March-April (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 1996 March-April: International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) -- lecture notes (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 1996 March-April: International Symposium on Diagnosis of Viral and Chlamydial Infections (Tainan, Taiwan) -- VRL charts and miscellaneous (Box 23, Folder 5)
      The charts of the VAMC Virology Reference Laboratory were possibly used in a presentation. Also included are business cards given to G.D. Hsiung of colleagues that she met.
    - 1997 Symposium on Clinical Virology and Bacteriology (Taiwan) - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 23, Folder 6)